ENTRY       M00222            Complex   Module
NAME        Phosphate transport system
DEFINITION  K02040+K02037+K02038+K02036
ORTHOLOGY   K02040  pstS; phosphate transport system substrate-binding protein
            K02037  pstC; phosphate transport system permease protein
            K02038  pstA; phosphate transport system permease protein
            K02036  pstB; phosphate transport system ATP-binding protein [EC:3.6.3.27]
CLASS       Structural complex; Environmental information processing; Phosphate and amino acid transport system
PATHWAY     map02010  ABC transporters
BRITE       ko02000  Transporters
COMMENT     Stoichiometry: 1:1:1:2
            Substrate: Orthophosphate [CPD:C00009]
DBLINKS     BSID: 890489
REFERENCE   PMID:8843165 (phosphate)
  AUTHORS   Braibant M, Lefevre P, de Wit L, Ooms J, Peirs P, Huygen K, Wattiez R, Content J.
  TITLE     Identification of a second Mycobacterium tuberculosis gene cluster encoding proteins of an ABC phosphate transporter.
  JOURNAL   FEBS Lett 394:206-12 (1996)
REFERENCE   PMID:8628229 (phosphate)
  AUTHORS   Nikata T, Sakai Y, Shibat K, Kato J, Kuroda A, Ohtake H.
  TITLE     Molecular analysis of the phosphate-specific transport (pst) operon of Pseudomonas aeruginosa.
  JOURNAL   Mol Gen Genet 250:692-8 (1996)
REFERENCE   PMID:9139906 (phosphate)
  AUTHORS   Lefevre P, Braibant M, de Wit L, Kalai M, Roeper D, Grotzinger J, Delville JP, Peirs P, Ooms J, Huygen K, Content J.
  TITLE     Three different putative phosphate transport receptors are encoded by the Mycobacterium tuberculosis genome and are present at the surface of Mycobacterium bovis BCG.
  JOURNAL   J Bacteriol 179:2900-6 (1997)
REFERENCE   PMID:8918249 (phosphate)
  AUTHORS   Braibant M, Lefevre P, de Wit L, Peirs P, Ooms J, Huygen K, Andersen AB, Content J
  TITLE     A Mycobacterium tuberculosis gene cluster encoding proteins of a phosphate transporter homologous to the Escherichia coli Pst system.
  JOURNAL   Gene 176:171-6 (1996)
REFERENCE   PMID:1447208 (phosphate)
  AUTHORS   Webb DC, Rosenberg H, Cox GB.
  TITLE     Mutational analysis of the Escherichia coli phosphate-specific transport system, a member of the traffic ATPase (or ABC) family of membrane transporters. A role for proline residues in transmembrane helices.
  JOURNAL   J Biol Chem 267:24661-8 (1992)
///
