ENTRY       M00332            Complex   Module
NAME        Type III secretion system
DEFINITION  K03221-K04056-K04057-K04059+K03219-K04058+K03222+K03226+K03227+K03228+K03229+K03230+K03224+K03225-K03223
ORTHOLOGY   K03221  yscF; type III secretion protein SctF
            K04056  yscO; type III secretion protein SctO
            K04057  yscP; type III secretion protein SctP
            K04059  yscX; type III secretion protein SctX
            K03219  yscC; type III secretion protein SctC
            K04058  yscW; type III secretion protein SctW
            K03222  yscJ; type III secretion protein SctJ
            K03226  yscR; type III secretion protein SctR
            K03227  yscS; type III secretion protein SctS
            K03228  yscT; type III secretion protein SctT
            K03229  yscU; type III secretion protein SctU
            K03230  yscV; type III secretion protein SctV
            K03224  yscN; ATP synthase in type III secretion protein SctN [EC:3.6.3.14]
            K03225  yscQ; type III secretion protein SctQ
            K03223  yscL; type III secretion protein SctL
CLASS       Structural complex; Environmental information processing; Bacterial secretion system
PATHWAY     map03070  Bacterial secretion system
BRITE       ko02044  Secretion system
COMMENT     Substrate: Effector proteins, Needle proteins, Components of the translocon
DBLINKS     BSID: 890586
REFERENCE   PMID:19396170
  AUTHORS   Spreter T, Yip CK, Sanowar S, Andre I, Kimbrough TG, Vuckovic M, Pfuetzner RA, Deng W, Yu AC, Finlay BB, Baker D, Miller SI, Strynadka NC
  TITLE     A conserved structural motif mediates formation of the periplasmic rings in the type III secretion system.
  JOURNAL   Nat Struct Mol Biol 16:468-76 (2009)
REFERENCE   PMID:15590783
  AUTHORS   Ghosh P
  TITLE     Process of protein transport by the type III secretion system.
  JOURNAL   Microbiol Mol Biol Rev 68:771-95 (2004)
REFERENCE   PMID:12360191
  AUTHORS   Cornelis GR
  TITLE     The Yersinia Ysc-Yop 'type III' weaponry.
  JOURNAL   Nat Rev Mol Cell Biol 3:742-52 (2002)
///
